# 你看 買了一個這個鋸子 去攝影小哥家砍樹
Look! I’ve bought this chain saw, to chop the tree at Mr. Cameraman’s place.
# 他家的板栗樹要砍掉哦 他家要做房子
His chestnuts tree needs to be chopped, cuz he wants to build a house.
# 所以趁機會把板栗 全部摘下來
So I have the chance. I'm gonna pick all the chestnuts there.
# 試一下啊 買了一個這個
Let me try. I’ve just bought it.
# 要穿這個安全褲才行的哦 要不然
We gotta put on this harness. Otherwise,
# 很危險的 要上那麼高的樹
it's too dangerous. We need to climb such a tall tree.
# 這個尺寸要調到自己合適 合適為準
The size needs to be adjusted to fit, fit myself.
# 剛搞這個就是不知道安不安全呢
I’ve just put this on but have no ideas if it's really save.
# 我去樹上掛一下我 看一下行不行
Let me hang myself onto the tree and see if it works.
# 我先試一下安不安全這個
Let me try if this is really safe, this harness.
# 可以啦 這樣挺安全的這樣
Alright. It’s rather safe this way.
# 這吊兩條豬都沒問題
It can easily stand the weight of two pigs.
# 可以哦
Not bad!
# 你看 我都可以掛在這裡
Look! I can hang myself onto the tree.
# 準備上樹啦 把這個
Let’s get ready. This one,
# 勾起來
hook it here.
# 這裡 這裡肯定撿的到 兩三百斤肯定撿的到的
Here, here, we can pick, I’m sure that we can pick up to at least a hundred and fifty kilograms.
# 好大顆 好大粒啊
It’s so big, really big!
# 你看 這樣就 很漂亮的哦 這種板栗
Look! This one is, really pretty, you know, this kind of chestnuts.
# 又大又圓
Big and round.
# 先把它撿回去 慢慢處理
Let me pick them all back first, and deal with them afterwards.
# 兩牛皮袋都滿啦
Two bags are completely filled.
# 先拱到那個麵包車上
Let’s lift it to our van first.
# 就搞了那麼一點點
So we have just a tiny little bit here.
# 好像六麻袋還是七麻袋
There seems to be six or seven bags.
# 回去啦
Let’s go back.
# 周個豬肚來 板栗煲豬肚
Let me fetch a pork bag, and stew it with the chestnuts.
# 第二天
The next day
# 都是瞉裡面看不出來的 一掰出來就是好的 (註︰我聽到他是說「是老的」)
We can’t see the chestnuts inside the shell. But once the shell is cracked, you'll see that it's old.
# 不是很老的板栗
These chestnuts are not really old.
# 是的 不是很老 但是也可以吃的哦 你看
Yup. Not very good. But they’re still edible, look!
# 那麼大
It’s so big.
# 先把這板栗剝一下
Let’s peel the chestnuts first.
# 先要一個個把它剝好
I gotta peel them one by one.
# 這個壞的 壞的就不要
This one is rotten. Pass.
# 要慢慢剝
It might take some time.
# 先吃一個先
Let me eat one first.
# 剛好今天人多啊 搞了3隻雞 在[SIC]搞了一點板栗
It just so happens that there are many people here today. I have fetched three chickens, and also some chestnuts,
# 加一個豬肚
together with a pork bag,
# 一鍋燉啦
then stew them all in the same pot.
# 這個雞在兄弟家
This chicken had been kept
# 養啦
at my,
# 養了差不多半年這個土雞
at my buddy’s place for more than half a year, this free range chicken.
# 沒甚麼肥肉的哦
There’s hardly any fat, you know.
# 這個雞腿
This chicken leg,
# 這個雞腿留著
leave this chicken leg in one piece.
# 好的食材不需要調料的哦 放點生薑就好啦
Good ingredients never need seasoning. A little bit of ginger is everything needed.
# 放到前面去 直接下鍋
Let me put it over there, and then into the pot right away.
# 把這個雞都放下去了
So I’m gonna put the chicken in.
# 哎呀 一大鍋
Aya! A big pot!
# 然後再把這個豬肚放下去 (註︰原字幕缺失了)
Then I put this pork bag in as well.
# 就直接在這樣
Then leave everything here right away.
# 然後直接蓋起來 大火燒
And then cover it up right away, and cook it on high heat.
# 燒一個小時就可以啦
Cook it for an hour. That’s it.
# 再搞一點板栗
Let me get some chestnuts as well.
# 這個板栗剝好了哦
These chestnuts have been peeled now.
# 等下我把它倒下去
I’ll put them into the pot in a while.
# 差點忘記啦 這個才是主食來的
I’ve almost forgotten. The protagonist is here,
# 這是板栗啊
the chestnuts.
# 加點鹽
Put some salt.
# 嗯 真的很好吃
Umhm! It’s really tasty.
# 不騙你們的
No kidding.
# 這個湯
The soup,
# 簡直是精華所在
is really where the essence is.
# 搞一個雞腿吃一下
Let me have a chicken leg.
# 這個雞腿
This chicken leg…
# 看到沒有 大長腿
See? It’s a big, long leg.
# 長而不油膩
Long, but not oily.
# 很好吃
It’s so tasty.
# 準備吃飯啦
It’s time for lunch now.
# 他們都餓的受不了啦
They’re nearly staving to death.
# 現在都快2點了
It will be two very soon.
# 那個煲一下湯煲的有點久
Making this soup took a bit longer than expected.
# 所以 好東西都是
So, good food always,
# 慢慢 慢慢燉出來的
takes, takes much more time.
# 嗯 好啦 準備吃飯啦
Um! Alright! Let’s have our lunch.
# 開吃開吃
Let’s start, let’s start!
# 吃飯咯 吃飯咯
Meal time, meal time!